gavin leech

(work in progress)

about

projects

Email Blog Github LinkedIn Reviews

Reversals in academic psychology (2020)

<u>Collated</u> the most striking outcomes of the replication crisis in psychology. Some reanalysis of the original data in Jupyter. Forthcoming on Andrew Gelman.

Hardening the browser (2019)

A beginner's guide to cybersecurity, with an emphasis on cost:benefit.

programming (in production)

Python/SciPy/Spark, Keras, *nix, Azure, C#, JS (ES6, node, TS), PHP, Pig, LaTeX, Powershell.

Side effects in Gridworlds (2018)

Teamwork on the side-effects problem in reinforcement learning. Implemented DQN and MaxEnt IRL in Tensorflow, created new environments, and evaluated their safety properties. Written up here, code here, code

The First Computers (2017)

Deployed. Conceptual analysis to solve a historical question, Transcrypt Python transpiler.

Py2HTK (2016)

On github. Wrapper for a venerable NLP library. Used in this research.

interests

open science, self-calibration, failures of reasoning, failures of reasoning about reasoning, lists.

publications

Inductive Logic Programming: Capabilities & Safety (forthcoming)

education

2019 – 2023 PhD Interactive Artificial Intelligence

University of Bristol

First year was a de facto research Master's, including foundations of probability and other uncertainty measures, NLP, computational logic, legal aspects of Al. Thesis on multiobjective optimisation.

2013 – 2019 BSc Mathematics & Statistics

The Open University

First: <u>89% GPA</u>. Probability up to diffusion processes, regression to GLMMs, numerics to BFGS, linear algebra to multi-linear, RCTs. Part-time during FT work. Reviewed here.

2018 Apache Spark Developer Certification

Databricks

For PySpark 2.x. Covered RDDs, DFs, SparkML, streaming, & advanced config in depth.

experience

2019 – Now **Resolution Council Judge**

Parallel Forecast, London

Judging outcomes for an AI prediction market. Topics include timelines, macroeconomics, state-of-the-art performance.

2016 - 2019 Data Scientist

AXA Insurance, London

Built dozens of ML models (GLMs, GBMs, deep ANNs) for actuarial pricing, medical risk, & image recognition. Tech lead for 5 scientists & engineers; web scraping at scale; migration from SAS to Hadoop, & Hadoop to Azure.

Buzzwords: Python, Spark, Keras, XGBoost, Tableau, Avro, Pytest, GDPR

2015 – 2016 Software Developer

Freetobook, Glasgow

Improved a large legacy accommodation engine: PHP back-end, JS frontend, REST APIs. Sole design of a PCI compliant credit-card storage system.

Buzzwords: PHP 5 & 7, LAMP, SQL, Laravel, cURL, Gitlab, New Relic.

2015 Software Developer

Stugo, Glasgow

Jumped into web dev; my code in worldwide production within 2 weeks. Products: a medicine pump device manager & a pharmacy record system.

Buzzwords: C#, WPF, node.JS, MEAN, Ractive, Mongo, Vagrant, VMWare.

2014 - 2015 Database Developer

STAND International, Edinburgh

Built a small ops database for an international NGO. Solo greenfield design & deployment; delivered at zero infrastructure and licence cost.

Buzzwords: MS Access, Office365, SQL, UML, data protection.

2014 Assistant Statistician

The Scottish Government, Edinburgh

Produced & explained official statistics in the Education Analytics division. Helped on a results reporting platform, giving teachers data & viz. Prep and design for the national Social Care Survey 2015.

Buzzwords: SAS, SQL, PCA, data protection.